# Waleed Daud

**J** (+92) 3091474765 ■ waleeddaud3gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/waleed-daud https://github.com/waleeddaud

# Objective

Software Engineering student and Junior Back-end Developer skilled in building RESTful APIs with FastAPI, Flask, and Express.js. Experienced in LLM integration via LangChain, Gemini, and OpenAI. Can develop basic ETL pipelines using Dagster. Compassion for problem solving, programming fundamentals, and DSA.

## Education

#### Bachelors in Software Engineering

2023 - Present CGPA: 3.85/4

Punjab University College of Information Technology (PUCIT), Lahore, Pakistan

Government College University Lahore(GCUL), Lahore, Pakistan

2019 - 2021Final Grade: 1098/1100

# Experience

Aviation Cadet

June 2022 – June 2023

Pakistan Air Force Academy Asghar Khan (PAFAA)

Risalpur, Pakistan

- Was commissioned as Aviation Cadet for Aerospace Engineering
- Participated in training focused on discipline, teamwork, and leadership. Participated in physical, and metal training exercises and critical thinking skills.
- Left training due to medical grounds.

### Junior Backend Developer

Nov 2024 – Present

CodeBryx

Lahore. Pakistan

- I gained hands-on experience working with Langchain, AI chatbots using OpenAI's Assistant API, and Gemini. Implementing RAG using Pinecone DB.
- I also worked on backend development using FastAPI/ Flask with SQLAlchemy, Node.js with Sequelize ORM, PostgreSQL, and . I was also involved in the implementation of JWT authentication for secure API.
- Working on ETL Data Pipelines using Dagster

### **Projects**

#### $BlogApp \mid FastAPI$

- Blog Management: Create, update, delete, and view blogs
- PostgreSQL Integration: Store and manage data
- Secure Authentication with JWT tokens
- GitHub Link

#### Event Management System | nodejs, Expressjs

- Description: Developed a backend for an event management system with secure authentication, role-based access control, and CRUD operations using Sequelize ORM
- GitHub Link

#### Technical Skills

Languages: Python, C++, JavaScript

Web & Frameworks: Flask, FastAPI, Expressis, PostgreSQL Generative AI: OpenAI, Gemini, LangChain, LLM Integration

Data Science & Data Engineering: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Dagster

Other Tools: Git/GitHub, VS Code